They're here.
Poltergeist is a horror film directed by Tobe Hooper.
The Freelings' suburban home becomes the center of paranormal
activity that opens a portal to the 'other side'.
With help, they must cross over to get their daughter back.
Diane Freeling, played by JoBeth Williams.
Steve Freeling, played by Craig T. Nelson.
Dr. Lesh, played by Beatrice Straight.
Dana Freeling, played by Dominique Dunne.
Carol Anne Freeling, played by Heather O'Rourke.
Robbie Freeling, played by Oliver Robins.
Poltergeist is a 1982 American supernatural horror film directed by Tobe Hooper and written by
Steven Spielberg, Michael Grais, and Mark Victor from a story by Spielberg.
It stars JoBeth Williams, Craig T.
Nelson, and Beatrice Straight, and was produced by Spielberg and Frank Marshall.
The film follows a suburban family whose home is invaded by
malevolent ghosts that abduct their youngest daughter.
As Spielberg was contractually unable to direct another film while he made E.T.
the Extra-Terrestrial, Hooper was selected based on his work on
The Texas Chain Saw Massacre and The Funhouse.
The origin of Poltergeist can be traced to Night Skies, which Spielberg conceived as a horror sequel to his 1977 film Close Encounters
of the Third Kind; Hooper was less interested in the sci-fi elements and suggested they collaborate on a ghost story.
Accounts differ as to the level of Spielberg's involvement, but it is clear that he was
frequently on set during filming and exerted significant creative control.
For that reason, some have said that Spielberg should be considered the film's co-director
or even main director, though both Spielberg and Hooper have disputed this.
Released by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer through MGM/UA Entertainment Co.
on June 4, 1982, Poltergeist was a major critical and commercial
success, becoming the eighth-highest-grossing film of 1982.
In the years since its release, the film has been
recognized as a horror classic.
It was nominated for three Academy Awards, named by the Chicago Film Critics Association as the
20th-scariest film ever made, and a scene made Bravo's 100 Scariest Movie Moments.
Poltergeist also appeared at No.
84 on American Film Institute's 100 Years...100 Thrills.
The film was followed by Poltergeist II: The Other Side (1986), Poltergeist III (1988),
and a 2015 remake, but none had the critical success of the original.
The film explores themes of dying and death, parent child
relationship, medium, poltergeist, halloween.
The tone is dark.